Amitava Saha

Full-Stack Javascript Developer / VP Engineering @ Gerald

Bangalore, India (+91) 7411239568 https://amitavasaha.com amitava82@gmail.com https://github.com/amitava82

I'm full-stack javascript developer with over 8 years professional experience building full stack web applications. My strength is in Node.Js backend and React, Redux ecosystem for UI. I have 8 years experience in Node.Js & I've been building React apps since last 4+ years.

Presently I'm working as VP Engineering at Gerald Inc, New York based startup. We're remote team distributed across US and India.

I have masters degree (MBA) from USA and I have experience working there as well. I worked with several startups throughout my career and tried to spin up few of mine as well. I understand the startup culture, responsibilities it calls for and fit well in similar environment.

SKILL SUMMARY

- Expert level experience building scalable Node.Js backend.& single page applications using React & Redux.
- Expertise in developing RESTful & GraphQL API using NodeJS and development of real-time app using Socket.IO.
- Experience in both SQL & NoSQL databases such as Mongo, Dynamodb,
 Firebase, RethinkDB, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, Redis etc.
- Experience in various AWS services, serverless application development using AWS Lambda and Google cloud platform.
- Advanced knowledge of web technologies (HTML5/CSS/LESS/SCSS/JS/SPA).
- Expert knowledge of Object Oriented Javascript, ES6/7, React, Redux, Saga, Thunk, Webpack, async design patterns & promises.
- Extremely good at understanding and implementing markups. Solid knowledge of style, presentation, and design.
- TDD Javascript development using Jasmine and mocha.
- General familiarity with current trends in front-end tools and frameworks.

EXPERIENCE

Gerald Inc, New York, US - VP Engineering

JUN 2018 - PRESENT

Gerald helps insurance companies transform their payments data into actionable insights. We're building payment solutions for insurance industry. We're startup from New York and 100% remote company.

- I lead the development & QA team. My day to day responsibilities includes writing code, brainstorm product roadmap with CEO and talk to customers, understand their requirements & help them with integration efforts.
- Attend daily scrum calls and hold technical meetings with the team.

Redloop Technologies PVT LTD, Bangalore, India - Founder

SEP 2016 - DEC 2018

Redloop Technologies Pvt Ltd is a Bangalore based development studio specializing building apps using Node.JS and React & React-Native.

- I started this company with the plan to expand my freelancing career into full fledged IT consulting company.
- I along with a small team worked with startups to help them launch their products.

Azuqua, Seattle, US - Lead Frontend Engineer

JAN 2014 - AUG 2016

- I was Full-stack developer at Azuqua. I worked on the webapp for Azuqua cloud integration platform using web technologies such as Nodejs, ReactJs, Redux, KnockoutJS (before migrating to React), ES6, Microsoft Azure etc.
- Being early member of the team, I was involved in brainstorming product features with CEO & CTO on daily basis.
- Was responsible for leading integration of Azuqua platform for D&B Excel addon for Google sheet.
- I was responsible for building & leading offshore team for Azuqua in Bangalore.

TeleradTech Pvt Ltd, Bangalore, India - Frontend Developer

JUNE 2011 - DEC 2013

- Design, develop frontend codebase. During my tenure with the company, I introduced Single Page Application design pattern to the CTO & team and lead the effort in modernizing traditional server rendered page to modern SPA & API based architecture.
- Implement semantic html markup, table-less UI.
- Develop and Implement UI widgets using jQuery, jQuery UI, and other jQuery libraries
- Implement realtime UI using Socket.IO and NodeJS.
- Solely responsible in design and development of data driven SPA using AngularJS and ASP.NET REST API.
- Developed HTML5 DICOM Viewer with capabilities of zooming, windowing, panning.

Citrix Systems, Fort Lauderdale, FL, USA - SAP SD Functional consultant

OCT 2008 - FEB 2009

- Conducting business study and coordinating with the team members for requirement mapping, functional design & integration, implementation.
- Understanding business requirements, identifying pain points in order to provide better solutions for smooth business transactions using SAP ERP.
- Holding review meeting with business and technical teams to monitor progress of the project and demonstrate developed solutions.

• I Was responsible for several critical business processes such as different order to cash scenarios, customer master data, credit management etc.

Sigma Analyst Inc, Rolling Meadows, IL, USA - Trainee SAP SD Functional consultant

MAR 2008 - SEP 2008

- Conceptualizing and implementing SAP Sales and Distribution module.
- Developing model company structure, blueprinting and solution development.
- Worked on support and documentation.

Eglobe Solutions, Bangalore, India - Web Designer, Lead

JUN 2005 - APR 2006

- Web design as per client requirements.
- Client interaction, mapping client's requirements and coordinating in development.

EDUCATION

Indiana University of Pennsylvania, Indiana, PA, USA - MBA, SCM Major 2006 - 2008

PES Institute of Applied Sciences, Bangalore, India - BSc

2002 - 2005

CERTIFICATION

CISCO, CCNA